- "六人行"前情提要   - 我是说我觉得我不像有女朋友了
- Previously on Friends:         - I don't feel like I have a girlfriend.
你要我辞掉工作让你觉得你有女朋友
You want me to quit my job so you can feel like you have a girlfriend?
- 这跟马克有关吗   - 天啊
- Is this about Mark?     - Oh, my God.
- 好吧 跟他无关   - 我的天啊
- Okay, it's not.     - Oh, my God.
我无法老是跟你吵这件事
I cannot keep having this fight with you!
听着 或许我们该休息一下
Look, ugh, maybe we should just take a break.
好吧 你说的对 我们休息一下
Fine. You're right. Let's, uh, take a break.
- 我们去吃冷冻优格吧   - 不
- Let's get some frozen yogurt.     - No.
我们该分手了
A break from us.
我们大吵一架 我跟他说我要分手
Then we had this big fight, and I said I wanted to take a break.
我不想分手
I don't want to take a break.
这太疯狂了
This is crazy.
我们能解决这个问题吗
Can't we work on this?
你要喝什么
What do you want to drink?
是谁在说话
Who's that?
没有啊
Nobody.
- 是马克吗   - 甜心 听着 他刚好…
- Is that Mark?     - Honey, look, he just...
对 我明白了
Yeah. Got it!
来跳舞吧 你结婚了吗
Hey, come dance. What are you, married?
我不在乎
Because that's okay.
（第二天早上）
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
周年纪念日晚餐吃得如何
How was the big anniversary dinner?
其实我们没吃晚餐
Well, we never actually got to dinner.
太棒了
Ha, ha, oh. Nice.
我们分手了
We kind of broke up instead.
什么
What? Aah!
天啊 连天花板都喷到了
My God! It's on the ceiling!
没关系
That's okay.
这比我的天花板沾了水果
This is more important than fruit...
更加重要
...on my ceiling.
你们分手了
You broke up?
对 没关系的 罗斯离开后 马克刚好过来
Yeah, but it's okay because when Ross left, Mark came over.
- 不 你跟马克   - 不 没事的 冷静点
- Oh, no! You and Mark?     - No, it's okay. Calm down.
马克跟我谈过
Mark and I talked...
我了解到我多爱你的笨哥哥
...and I realized how much I love your stupid brother.
我们是有一些问题 我真的想解决
We got our problems, but I really wanna make it work.
早安
Morning!
# 没有人告诉你活着有多累 #
# So no one told you life was gonna be this way #
# 上班受罪 口袋空空 爱情变累赘 #
# Your job's a joke, you're broke, your love life's D.O.A. #
# 寂寞又潦倒 受气又受累 #
# It's like you're always stuck in second gear #
# 日复一日 年复一年 #
# When it hasn't been your day, #
# 时运不济 活着受罪 #
# your week, your month, or even your year #
# 你我永不离弃 #
# but I'll be there for you #
# 纵有狂风暴雨 #
# When the rain starts to pour #
# 你我永不离弃 #
# I'll be there for you #
# 支持一如往昔 #
# Like I've been there before #
# 你我永不离弃 #
# I'll be there for you #
# 你我相偎相依 #
# 'Cause you're there for me too #
嗨 是我
Hi, it's me.
我整晚都在找你 我真的好难过
I've been trying to reach you all night. I feel awful.
求求你 罗斯 你得知道我跟马克没什么
Please, Ross, you've got to know, there's nothing between me and Mark.
分手这件事太蠢了
This whole breakup thing is just stupid.
抱歉 我让你受苦了
Ugh, I'm sorry I put you through it.
我不想通过答录机跟你复合
And I don't want to get back together over a machine.
我爱你
So I love you.
I love you.
你知道吗 我要睡了
And you know what? I'm gonna go to bed now...
不过明天我去上班的时候 八点半会顺道去你家 再见
...but on my way to work tomorrow, I'll stop by around 8:30. Bye.
可洛 你还好吗
Chloe, how's it coming?
你觉得我该春哪种狗
What kind of puppy do you think I should get?
我不知道 何不养只大狗
Um, oh, hey. I don't know. How about a big one?
- 但我的公寓很…   - 那就养只小狗
- But my apartment's so...     - Then a small one.
- 你得走了   -  等一下 我的鞋子在哪里
- We have to go.     - Wait! Where's my shoes?
你需要鞋子吗
You need shoes?
-为什么我们要这么赶   -还记得我跟你说的女朋友吗
- Do I know why we're rushing?     - You know my girlfriend?
结果她想跟我复合
It turns out that she, uh, wants to get back together.
我找到了
I found it!
我为你们感到到高兴
That's so great for you guys!
你一定很开心
You must be so happy!
对 那是我现在的感触之一
Yes, I am. One of the many things I'm feeling.
- 祝你跟你女朋友一切顺利   - 谢谢
- Good luck with your girlfriend.     - Oh, thank you. Ah, eh.
瑞秋
Rachel!
- 你听到我的留言了吗   - 你还真是准时
- You got my message?     - You are right on time!
怎样 我能再当你的女朋友吗
So can I be your girlfriend again?
当然可以
Yes, you can. Very much.
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
- 为什么你在擦天花板   - 香蕉黏在上面了
- Why are you mopping your ceiling?     - Ugh, there's banana on it.
有个印第安老女人的灵魂住在我的身体里
I have the spirit of an old Indian woman living in mine.
那么你应该了解
So then you know.
邮差刚好过来 我帮你把邮件拿上楼
The mailman was here, so I brought your mail.
- 太好了 谢谢   - 法布科技是什么东西
- Oh, good. Thanks.     - Now, what is Fabutech?
别批评我 好吗
Okay. Don't judge me too much, okay?
我看到广告 我发誓我从来没有
I saw this infomercial, and, um, I swear I have never...
在电视购物频道买过东西
...bought anything on TV before.
除了这支拖把
Except for this mop.
但这个腿部蜜蜡除毛产品看起来超棒的
But there was this stuff on leg-waxing, it looked amazing.
- 蜜蜡除毛   - 对 你看到了吗
- Waxine!     - Yes! Have you seen it?
太不可思议了 我想当蜜蜡除毛女郎
It's incredible! I want to be a Waxine Girl!
我知道
I know!
天啊 你觉得真的不会痛吗 他们是怎么办到的
God! Do you think it really doesn't hurt? How can they do that?
最近在雨林发现的有机物质
Hello! Organic substances recently discovered in the rain forest?
那里的东西是最棒的了
They have the best stuff in there.
天啊
Oh, my God!
我们找不到你时 以为你跑回家跟瑞秋复合了
We figured when we couldn't find you, you'd gone to make up with Rachel.
或许你该那么做
Which is probably what you should have done, huh? Heh.
你真的那么认为吗
You think?
天啊 我真的好痛苦 我该怎么办
God, I'm in hell. I mean, what am I gonna do?
瑞秋一直说我爱你 我满脑子只想着
Rachel's all "I love you," and all I can think about...
如果我跟她说我做的好事 她会有什么反应
...is what is she gonna do when I tell her what I did?
首先我们该强调一下重点
First, we should address the more important question...
你到底有多笨呢
...how dumb are you?
什么听着 我们想复合
What? Look, we're trying to rebuild a relationship here, right?
不诚实以对 我该怎么跟她复合
How am I supposed to do that without being honest?
罗斯 我完全支持诚实以对那一点
I'm on board about the total-honesty thing. I am.
但别说出 会害你惹上麻烦的事
Just not about stuff that's gonna get you in trouble.
他说的对 这对大家没好处 你只会伤害她
He's right. Nobody benefits, and you'll just hurt her.
而你们不会有机会复合的
And there won't be a relationship left to rebuild.
你不觉得…
Don't you think...?
如果你非告诉她不可 至少等到时机成熟
If you have to tell her, at least wait till the timing's right.
那是临终遗言的真正意义
And that's what deathbeds are for.
- 好吧   - 太棒了
- Yeah, okay.     - All right.
好吧 我们得确定她不会从别的地方知道这件事
Okay. Now, we just have to make sure she doesn't find out some other way.
你有考虑切断关联吗
Did you think about the trail?
什么关联
What trail?
跟你一起做的女人
From the woman you did it with...
与你不希望她知道这件事的女人
...to the woman you hope never finds out you did it!
一定要切断关联
Always think about the trail!
我想她们没有关联
I don't think there's any trail.
好吧
Okay, okay.
可洛跟艾萨克是同事
Chloe works with that guy, Isaac.
艾萨克的姊姊是杰丝敏 她跟菲比是按摩店的同事
Isaac's sister is Jasmine, who works at the massage place with Phoebe.
菲比是瑞秋的同事 那是她们的关联 我找到了
Phoebe is Rachel's friend, and that's the trail! I did it!
将蜜蜡涂在腿上 贴好亚麻布
"After applying the Waxine and linen strips to leg..."
- 好了   - 好的
- Did that!     - Okay.
抓住亚麻布的末端
"Grasp the linen strip by its tab...
快速地将它往上扯
...and pull it off in one quick...
- 完全不会痛   - 好的
...pain-free motion."     - Okay.
不是不会痛吗
Was it not "pain-free"?
不 是痛死了
No, it was pain-ful!
天啊 他们该叫它超痛蜜蜡除毛
My God, they should call it "Pain-zine, now with a little wax."
广告里的女孩似乎觉得这不是一个烂主意
The girls on the commercial don't seem to think it's that bad.
因为她们笨到神经麻木了
Because their nerves are deadened from being so stupid.
如果你不相信 自己试试看吧
But, you know, if you don't believe me, please be my guest.
天啊
Ow, ow, ow! Oh, my God!
你很高兴我们没先做比基尼线除毛了吧
Now are you glad we didn't start with the bikini strips?
可洛
Chloe, hi.
你来质问我拿走你手表的事吗
Is this about me taking your watch?
- 你拿走我的手表   - 抱歉 我会这么做
- You took my watch?     - I'm sorry. I do that.
手表送你 听着 你有跟任何人提起我们的事吗
You keep it. Listen, did you tell anyone about us?
不 我觉得那不关别人的事
Oh, no. I feel like it really isn't anybody's business.
没错 你什么都没跟艾萨克说吧
Exactly. So you didn't mention anything to Isaac?
- 我什么事都跟艾萨克说   - 是吗 那当然
- Oh, I tell Isaac everything.     - You do? Of course you do.
艾萨克 我们没有正式介绍过
Hi, Isaac. You know, we haven't actually met.
你超猛的
You dog!
我想我是超猛的 听着 我刚好有女朋友
Yes, I suppose I am a dog. But see, I happen to have a girlfriend.
对 咖啡厅的瑞秋
Right. Rachel from the coffee place.
就是她 听着 我不想伤害她
That's the one. Listen, I don't want to hurt her.
我了解 不论我们多爱她们
Oh, hey, man, I know. It doesn't matter how much we love them.
一夫一妻制真的很残忍
Monogamy is too cruel a rule.
对 听着 你能帮我保密吗
Yeah. Listen, can you keep this information to yourself?
没问题 我们得罩彼此
Oh, no problem. We gotta look out for each other.
你跟我是一丘之貉
We're the same, you and me.
事实上 我们不是的
Actually, no, we're not. Heh.
对 我们就是
Yeah, we are.
不 不是的
No, we're not.
对 就是
Yeah, we are.
不 不是的
No, we're not.
- 好吧 不是的   - 对
- Okay, we're not.     - Right.
不过事实上就是
But we are.
好吧 我只是要知道你没跟你姊姊说
Fine. I just need to know that you're not gonna tell your sister.
我可以保证不会再跟她提
I can promise not to tell her again.
杰丝敏
Jasmine?
我们在菲比的生日派对上见过面 我是罗斯•盖勒
We met at Phoebe's birthday party. I'm Ross Geller.
你做了坏事
You did a bad thing!
- 没错   - 非常坏
- Yes, I did.     - Very bad!
- 非常坏   - 对 超级坏
- Very bad.     - Very, very bad!
我同意你的说法
I'm agreeing with you.
听着 你跟菲比说了吗
Listen, did you happen to tell Phoebe yet?
- 还没有   - 好的 杰丝敏
- No.     - Okay. Jasmine.
求求你别跟她说
Please. Please don't.
我非常爱我的女朋友 我希望能跟她有结果
I love my girlfriend very much and I want to work it out with her.
好吧
All right.
谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
不过你该跟我的室友谈 因为我跟他说了 他也认识菲比
But you should talk to my roommate. I told him, and he knows Phoebe too.
你的室友是谁
Who's your roommate?
阿甘
Gunther! Gunther!
请跟我说你没告诉瑞秋我跟影印店女孩的事
Tell me you didn't tell Rachel about me and the girl from the copy place.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不该说吗
Was I not supposed to?
- 我们没事   - 没事的
- We're all right.     - It's okay. It's okay.
- 我们只是在做腿部蜜蜡除毛   - 是吗
- Ooh! We were just waxing our legs.     - Off?
我得说这是男人不懂的痛苦
For your information, this is a pain like no man will ever experience.
你无权那么说 除非你也被踢到
You can't make that statement unless you've been kicked in an area...
上帝要我们好好保护的地方
...that God only meant to be treated nicely.
女人的忍痛能力就是没有男人好
Women just have a lower threshold for pain than men, that's all.
少来了 只是蜜蜡除毛而已
I mean, come on, it's just a little wax. Heh.
是吗 过来
Oh, yeah? Come here.
那还真是成熟
Oh, that's mature.
现在只要把它撕下来
So now I just pull it off?
没错
That's right.
瑞秋 别这样 跟我说话 拜托
Rachel, come on. Just talk to me. Please!
- 现在我无法看着你   - 什么
- I can't look at you right now.     - What?
没事
Nothing. Nothing.
- 她说一切都没事的啊   - 他们在说什么
- She said it was okay.     - What are they talking about?
- 离我远一点   - 我错了 好吗
- Just get away from me!     - I made a mistake, okay?
你错了 你想把你的宝贝放在哪里 她的皮包里
A mistake? What were you trying to put it in? Her purse?
他把他的宝贝放在哪里
Whe...? Where did he put it?
罗斯 你跟别的女人上床
You had sex with another woman!
天啊
Oh, my God!
我就知道出事了 因为昨天我的指甲没有变长
I knew something was wrong because my nails didn't grow at all yesterday.
我猜他们吵了一架 他喝醉了
I guess they had a fight, and he got drunk...
你们知道这件事 却没有告诉我们
You guys knew about this and didn't tell us?
他跟女人上床 结果是我们被打头
He has sex, and we get hit in our heads!
- 我要你离开 快给我滚出去   - 不
- I want you to leave! Get out! Now!     - No! No!
我要留下来跟你谈清楚
I want to stay and talk about this.
好吧 她的功夫如何
Okay! All right. How was she?
- 什么   - 她很厉害吗
- What?     - Was she good?
别回答那个问题
Don't answer that.
你说你要谈的 来谈吧 她的功夫如何
You said you wanted to talk about it. Let's talk. How was she?
- 她…   - 很可怕
- She was...     - Awful.
- 一点都不棒   - 超逊的 比不上你
- She was not good.     - Horrible. Nothing compared to you.
她不一样
She... She was different.
很好的不一样
Good different?
没有人喜欢改变
Nobody likes change.
- 住口   - 什么好吧
- Just stop!     - What? Okay! Okay! Okay!
我们该想想办法吗
Should we do something?
对 千万别背叛瑞秋
Yeah. Never cheat on Rachel.
对不起 好吗 连我都讨厌我自己
I'm sorry, okay? I'm sorry. I was disgusted with myself...
今天早上我好难过
...and this morning I was upset...
我听到你的留言时开心极了
...and then I got your message, and I was so happy.
我只希望她能离开我的公寓
And all I wanted was to get her out of my apartment...
等一下
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Wait a minute.
你的小朋友何时离开的
What time did your little friend leave?
天啊 当时她还在那里
Oh, my God. She was there? She was still there?
我在那里时 她也在
She was in there when I was in there?
听着 重点是她对我而言毫无意义
Listen, the important thing is, she meant nothing to me.
但她却能毁了我们的关系
And yet she was worth jeopardizing our relationship!
那时我以为我们之间毁了
I didn't think there was a relationship.
- 我以为我们分手了     -  我们只是分开一下
- We'd broken up.   - We were on a break.
我只知道那可能会是永远 跟分手是一样的意思
That, for all I knew, could last forever. That is a breakup.
你想用技术问题脱困
You're gonna get out of this on a technicality?
我没有想到脱困问题
I'm not trying to "get out" of anything.
我以为我们之间结束了
I thought our relationship was dead.
你真的很会挑出轨时间
Well, you sure had a hell of a time at the wake.
我想我们不该再听下去了
I don't think we should listen to this anymore.
你在做什么我们不能出去
What are you doing? We can't go out.
为什么 我饿了
Why not? I'm hungry.
他们会知道我们一直在偷听
Because they'll know we've been listening.
天啊 我还得让阿甘来告诉我
God! And to have to hear about it from Gunther!
少来了 我跑遍全城只为了确定不会发生那种事
Come on, I ran all over the place trying to make sure that didn't happen!
那真是贴心
Oh, that is so sweet.
我想我又爱上你了
I think I'm falling in love with you all over again.
我们可以出去 他们还有别的事要担心
We can go out. They have other things to worry about.
我们会没事的
We'll be fine.
瑞秋 我想告诉你 我觉得我该告诉你
Rachel, I wanted to tell you. I thought I should.
但钱德跟乔伊说服我别那么做
And then Chandler and Joey convinced me not to!
用蜜蜡把门封住 我们永远都不要出去
Wax the door shut. We're never leaving.
我是菲比 得有人帮我接九点的班 为雷哈克先生服务
It's Phoebe. Someone has to take my 9:00 with Mr. Rehak...
因为现在是9点15分 我还没有到店里
...because it's 9: 15 now, and I'm not there.
难道你不知道不该发生这种事的 要不是我以为
None of this would've happened if I didn't think...
你跟马克上床了
...you were having sex with Mark.
好吧
All right.
就说我跟马克上床了 你会原谅我吗
Let's say I had slept with Mark. Would you have been able to forgive me?
我会的
Yes, I would.
你能接受马克吻我 跟我坦诚相见
You'd be okay if Mark had kissed me and been naked with me...
和我做爱吗
...and made love to me?
当然可以
Yes.
如果你知道我们火烫汗湿的身体…
If you knew that our hot, sweaty, writhing bodies were...
好吧 我会非常抓狂
Okay. Okay, yeah. I would have been devastated...
但我还是想跟你在一起
...but I would still want to be with you.
因为是你
Because, I mean, it's you.
什么
What?
快告诉我你在想什么
Come on, tell me what you're thinking.
我在想…
I'm thinking...
我要叫比萨
...I'm gonna order a pizza.
叫比萨的意思是…
Order a pizza, like...
"我原谅你了"
..."I forgive you"?
天啊
Oh, man!
比萨
Pizza?
我喜欢比萨
I like pizza.
在比萨上面加橄榄
Put olives on the pizza.
我们可以吃蜜蜡 它是有机蜜蜡
We could eat the wax! It's organic!
太棒了 有毛的食物
Oh, great. Food with hair on it.
不是吃用过的蜜蜡
No, not the used wax.
因为那么做的话就太疯狂了
Because that would be crazy?
可以算我一份吗 因为我也饿了
Could I get in on that? Because I'm kind of hungry myself.
好吧
Fine.
我要订大份比萨
Yes, I'd like to order a large pizza.
- 不要缇鱼   - 多加些缇鱼
- No anchovies.     - With, uh, extra anchovies.
没关系 我可以挑出来
That's okay. I'll pick them off.
拜托你切一下加在酱汁里
And could you chop some up and put it right in the sauce?
如果你要的话 最后一块给你吃
You can have the last piece if you want.
那应该是我的比萨 你跟别人上床
Well, I should think so. You slept with someone.
他们会度过这个难关 对吧
They're gonna get through this, aren't they?
当然 少来了 他们是罗斯与瑞秋
Yeah. Come on, it's Ross and Rachel.
他们非得撑过来不可
They've got to.
如果他们真的分手呢
What if they don't?
你们觉得我需要换新走路方式吗
You think I need a new walk?
什么
What?
我从高中以后就用相同的方式走路
Well, I've been walking the same way since high school.
你们知道有些人一走进来 大家会立刻注意到他吗
You know how some guys walk into a room and everybody takes notice?
我想我得用会引起大家注意的方式走路
I think I need a take-notice walk.
你是认真的吗
Are you actually saying these words?
怎么现在你连话都不跟我说了
What, now you're not even talking to me?
听着 瑞秋 对不起 我疯了
Look, Rachel, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I was out of my mind.
我以为我失去你了 我不知道该怎么做
I thought I'd lost you.
拜托…我一定是疯了 才会做出那种事吧
How insane must I have been to do something like this?
我不会外遇 对吧 那不是我的作风 我不是乔伊
I don't cheat, right? That's not me. I'm not Joey!
对 好吧
Yeah, okay.
嘿
Hey.
已经凌晨三点了 他们不知道我回家了
It's 3 a.m. They don't know that I've come home yet.
你们注意到他们根本没担心我在哪里吗
You notice how they aren't wondering where I am?
对 有些人真的很自大
You know, people can be so self-involved.
你知道吗 想分手的人不是我
You know what? I'm not the one that wanted that break.
放弃的人是你 面对难关时
You're the one that bailed. You're the one...
想要逃走的人是你
...that ran the moment things got rough.
- 那是…   - 什么
- That's...     - That's what?
- 那跟这件事无关   - 好吧
- That is neither here nor there.     - Here we are...
我们谈到重点了 你打算怎么办
...in a spot again. What do you want?
你要如何处理这件事 你要为我们奋斗或放弃
How do you want to handle it? You want to fight for us or bail?
听着 我…
Look, I...
我做了一件很可怕的白痴蠢事
I did a terrible, stupid, stupid thing, okay?
对不起 我希望一切没发生过 但那是不可能的
I'm sorry. I wish I could take it back, but I can't.
我只是不想放弃我们之间美好的一切
I just can't see us throwing away something we know is so damn good.
我真的很爱你
I love you so much.
不 罗斯 不要
No, Ross! Don't!
你不能想用一个吻解决所有问题
You can't just kiss me and make it all go away.
那是行不通的 没办法解决问题
It doesn't work that way. It doesn't just make it better.
- 好吗   - 好吧
- Okay?     - Okay, okay.
我想你该离开了
I think you should go.
什么
What?
我想你真的该离开了
I really think you need to go now.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
今天早上你说没有我们解决不了的问题
This morning you said there was nothing we couldn't work past it.
那时我又知道什么
What the hell did I know?
我们一定有办法度过这个难关 好吗
There's got to be a way we can work past this. Okay?
我无法想像没有你的生活
I can't imagine my life without you.
你知道吗 没有…
You know? Without...
没有你的手
Without these arms...
你的脸 你的心
...and your face and heart...
你的好心肠 瑞秋 还有…
...your good heart, Rach, and...
不
No.
我没办法 现在你在我心中已经是另一个人了
I can't. You're a totally different person to me now.
以前我相信你永远不会伤害我
I used to think of you as somebody that would never, ever hurt me.
永远不会
Ever.
现在我无法停止想像你跟她在一起的样子
Now I can't stop picturing you with her.
我没办法 不论你说了什么或做了什么
I can't. It doesn't matter what you say or what you do.
那件事改变了一切
It's just changed everything.
永远地改变了
Forever.
不该是这样的
This can't be it.
为什么会这样呢
Then how come it is?
他们很久没说话了
They've been quiet for a long time.
或许她杀了他
Maybe she killed him.
我们走吧
Let's go.
那是你的新走路方式
Is that your new walk?
不 我快尿出来了
No. I really have to pee.